typing.com 2019-10-14

# Privacy Policy - Typing.com

###### Privacy Policy Updated: September 2019

Typing.com has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. This privacy policy applies to information, including personal information, that Typing.com (a product of Teaching.com) collects about you when you visit our website. This policy does not apply to other Teaching.com websites or apps.

Typing.com offers both a free (Student and Teacher), ad-supported version and a premium (Student and Teacher), subscription-based version. The personal information that we collect, use, share, and disclose is dependent upon the version utilized.

While most of Typing.com is a general audience website through which we do not knowingly collect information from children under 13, the teacher portal portion of our site contains features for teachers (such as grading and reporting on performance) designed for students who may be Children.

###### Information We Collect

We collect information from you directly when you create an account. Typing.com and third-party advertisers (only with our free versions), such as [ Google Ad Manager](https://admanager.google.com/home/) and [ Freestar](https://freestar.io/) may send one or more cookies to your browser to help customize your experience on our site and/or to provide you with ads that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to understand your choices about not having this information used by these companies, check out [ Network Advertising Initiative](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

You may establish an account with Typing.com by providing us with a username and password, and optionally, an email address. By establishing an account, you can save and track your performance on our site. If you establish an account with us, we will collect information about your performance on our site. If you do not establish an account, we will use a cookie to collect and track information about your performance. You also can establish an account to use our site by logging in through social media networks and other services, such as Clever Single Sign-On, Facebook or Google. If you do, we may collect certain personal information through the social network, including your full name and email address.

Typing.com uses advertising services provided by [ Google Ad Manager](https://admanager.google.com/home/) and [ Freestar](https://freestar.io/) that will collect information in order to target ads to you (only with our free versions). This may include your IP address, the identity of your Internet Service Provider, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, and the pages visited while on our site.

###### Sharing and Use of Information

We use the information described above to communicate with you, manage and improve our site, and for security purposes. Except as provided below, we will not sell, share, or disclose information we collect from or about you. Our site uses [ Google Analytics](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/). Google Analytics places a cookie on your web browser and collects your domain/IP address and/or device identifier. We use this information to diagnose problems and to improve and administer the site.

We share information with [ Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/), payment processing software, to process subscription payments from our users. We may allow this provider access to your personal information when necessary, subject to confidentiality agreements consistent with this policy.

We use [ Google Ad Manager](https://admanager.google.com/home/) and [ Freestar](https://www.freestar.io/) to serve ads to the users of our free versions. We provide advertisers with aggregated, de-identified information about our users. Through Google, advertisers may place and read cookies on your browser or use web beacons to collect information through an ad appearing on our site. Any advertisements served by Google may be controlled using the DoubleClick cookie which allows Google to display ads based on your visits to this and other sites. See the privacy policy for Google Ad Exchange for additional information.

We will share information if required in order to comply with the law or to protect ourselves against third party claims.

###### Security

No data transmission or storage over the internet is 100% secure. While we use security measures to protect your personal information, we cannot promise or guarantee absolute security.

###### Children’s Information

Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to create their own, free student account on Typing.com without consent from a parent or legal guardian. If you are the parent or legal guardian of someone under the age of 13 who may have provided us with information without your knowledge or consent, please contact us at [ support@typing.com](mailto:support@typing.com) to have this information removed. If you know of anyone under the age of 13 who may have provided us with information, please report it to us at [ support@typing.com](mailto:support@typing.com).

A parent may provide consent and purchase the premium student account for their child. As noted above, our teacher portal is designed for teachers that may have students that are children, and we may collect information directly from children under 13 in connection with this portion of the site. In compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”), see the following regarding the use of our site by children.

Children may use our School Edition provided that the school has complied with its responsibilities under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA") and COPPA. If a teacher or school official has consented to our collection of information from children who are students in a manner consistent with COPPA, we will collect and use such personal information. This consent can be revoked and the students information removed at anytime. For parental and legal guardian rights, see specific section below. Contained within this privacy policy we provide each school with all the notices required under COPPA.

###### Parent’s Rights

Parents have the right to review and request that Typing.com delete any personal information that the site has collected and retained about their child. If you would like to request that we delete any personal information we may have about your child (such as username, password, and performance information) or to request no further collection of personal information from your child, please contact us at [ support@typing.com](mailto:support@typing.com) or write to us at: 

PO Box 9241   
Santurce Station,   
San Juan, Puerto Rico   
00908

###### Links to Other Sites

As noted above, we use a third-party to deliver ads to our free version users. If you click on a link to a third party site, you will be taken to websites we do not control. This policy only applies to the practices of Typing.com. We are not responsible for these third party sites. Our site may also serve third party content that contains their own cookies or tracking mechanisms.

###### International Visitors

If you do not live in the United States, know that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using our site, you consent to the collection, transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States.

###### Questions or Concerns

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at [ support@typing.com](mailto:support@typing.com) or write to us at: 

PO Box 9241   
Santurce Station,   
San Juan, Puerto Rico   
00908

###### Policy Changes

Typing.com may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes to our Policy as required by law. We will also post an updated copy on our website. Please check our site periodically for updates.
